<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Luke's Cookbook</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/</link><description>Recent content on Luke's Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 17:25:53 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cabbage Tarte Tatin</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/cabbage-tarte-tatin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 17:25:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/cabbage-tarte-tatin/</guid><description>Ingredients Ingredient Subheading 1/2 recipe Buttery, Flaky Pie Dough or store-bought dough (see note) 1/2 cup granulated sugar (4 ounces; 113g) 6 tablespoons white balsamic vinegar (3 ounces; 90ml), divided 2 tablespoons unsalted butter (1 ounce; 28g) 1 tablespoon (15ml) Dijon mustard 2 teaspoons chopped fresh thyme leaves, plus more for garnish 1 1/2 teaspoons (5g) Diamond Crystal kosher salt; for table salt, use half as much by volume or the same weight 1/4 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper 1 small green cabbage head (2 to 3 pounds; 908 to1.</description></item><item><title>Crack Slaw</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/crack-slaw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 17:15:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/crack-slaw/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons toasted sesame oil 3 cloves garlic, minced 1/2 cup onion, diced 5 green onions, sliced on a bias (white and green parts) 1 pound ground pork 1/2 teaspoon ground ginger sea salt and black pepper, to taste 1 tablespoon Sriracha or garlic chili sauce, more to taste 14 ounce bag coleslaw mix (green cabbage, red cabbage and carrots) 3 tablespoons soy sauce 1 tablespoon unseasoned rice vinegar 2 tablespoons toasted sesame seeds Directions Heat the sesame oil in a large skillet over medium high heat.</description></item><item><title>Ham Pot Pie</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/ham_pot_pie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 17:27:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/ham_pot_pie/</guid><description>Ingredients Filling 3 tablespoons unsalted butter 1 pinch salt, or to taste 1/2 cup diced onions 1/3 cup diced carrots 1/3 cup diced celery 1/3 cup all-purpose flour 2 cups chicken broth 1/4 cup cream 1 cup cubed ham 1teaspoon minced fresh rosemary 1/4 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper 1 pinch cayenne pepper 1/4 cup water, or as needed 1/2 cup frozen peas Hot Water Pastry 2 1/4 cups all-purpose flour 1 teaspoon kosher salt 8 tablespoons unsalted butter 1/2 cup plus 1 tablespoon water, or as needed Egg Wash 1 large egg 1 teaspoon water Directions Melt butter with a pinch of salt in a saucepan over medium high heat, and sauté onions, carrot, and celery until onions turn translucent, 3 to 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Pizza Dough</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/pizza_dough/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 17:27:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/pizza_dough/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 teaspoons active dry yeast or instant yeast 7/8 to 1 1/8 cups (198g to 255g) lukewarm water* 2 tablespoons (25g) olive oil 3 cups (360g) King Arthur Unbleached All-Purpose Flour 1 1/4 teaspoons (8g) table salt Directions If you&amp;rsquo;re using active dry yeast, dissolve it, with a pinch of sugar, in 2 tablespoons of the lukewarm water. Let the yeast and water sit at room temperature for 15 minutes, until the mixture has bubbled and expanded.</description></item><item><title>Poolish</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/poolish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 17:27:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/poolish/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 part flour by weight 1 part water by weight yeast Directions Combine Throw it in the fridge Let it set Use part of it to start bread Feed it a 50/50 mix of flour and water</description></item><item><title>Japanese Milk Bun</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/japanese-milk-bun/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 08:54:49 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/japanese-milk-bun/</guid><description>This recipe is stolen and modified from King Arthur 1 which also provides an introduction to tangzhong 2 as well as a way to convert any bread recipe to use tangzhong 3.
Ingredients Tangzhong 6 tablespoons (86g) boiling water 2 tablespoons (14g) Unbleached Flour (any kind) Dough 2 1/2 cups (300g) Unbleached Bread Flour 2 tablespoons (14g) Dry Milk or nonfat dry milk 1/4 cup (50g) granulated sugar 1 teaspoon (6g) table salt 1 tablespoon instant yeast 1/2 cup (113g) milk, whole preferred 1 large egg 4 tablespoons (57g) unsalted butter, melted Directions Tangzhong Easy Method 4 Boil water in an electric kettle.</description></item><item><title>Egg Nog - Cooked</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/egg-nog-cooked/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 08:53:18 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/egg-nog-cooked/</guid><description>Ingredients 6 large eggs 2 large egg yolks ½ cup sugar plus 2 additional tablespoons ¼ teaspoon table salt 4 cups milk ½ cup brandy, bourbon, or dark rum 1 1 tablespoon vanilla extract ½ teaspoon nutmeg, plus extra for garnish ½ cup heavy cream, chilled Directions Whisk the eggs, yolks, sugar, and salt together in a large saucepan. Slowly whisk in the milk until well combined. Cook the mixture over low heat, stirring constantly, until the mixture is thick enough to coat the back of a spoon and registers a maximum of 160 degrees on an instant-read thermometer, about 25 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Basic White Bloomer</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/white-bloomer-bread/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 11:43:17 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/white-bloomer-bread/</guid><description>Ingredients Ingredient Subheading 4 cups (500g) strong white bread flour, plus extra for dusting 2 tsp salt 2 tsp dried yeast 3 tbsp olive oil 10 oz (320ml) cool water (1.25 cups) Directions Tip the flour into a large mixing bowl and add the salt to one side of the bowl and the yeast to the other. Add the oil and 240ml of the water. Use the fingers of one hand to mix the ingredients together.</description></item><item><title>Quiche</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/quiche/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 08:51:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/quiche/</guid><description>Ingredients Ingredient Subheading 1 Deep dish pie crust 1/4 cup Sour cream 8 large Eggs 1/4 cup Cream Salt Pepper Cayenne Pepper Hearty Bits (Cook&amp;rsquo;s Choice) I tend to use whatever is left over in the kitchen
Broccoli Peas Shredded Cheddar Onions Bacon Whatever tastes good Directions Prepare crust Pre-heat oven to 350F Take pie crust directly from freezer Gently poke holes in crust bottom without poking through pie tin or cracking crust Par-bake crust at 350F for 15 mins Prepare quiche Sautee any ingredients that require a little pre-cooking such as onions In a large bowl, mix eggs, sour cream, and cream together.</description></item><item><title>Chicken and Dumplings</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/chicken_and_dumplings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 19:55:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/chicken_and_dumplings/</guid><description>Ingredients Soup 3 tablespoons unsalted butter 1/4 pound skinless, boneless chicken, cubed Breast or thighs is fine, your choice 1 yellow onion, diced 1/3 cup flour salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste 1 pinch cayenne pepper 6 cups chicken broth 2 celery, diced 1 large carrot, diced 1/2 teaspoon fresh thyme leaves (Optional) 2 tablespoons sliced green onions Dumplings 1/2 cup farmer&amp;rsquo;s cheese 1 1 large egg 1 1/4 teaspoons minced fresh rosemary 1/2 teaspoon kosher salt, or to taste 1 pinch freshly ground black pepper 1/2 cup self-rising flour 1 pinch cayenne pepper Directions Soup Melt butter in a high saucepan with a lid over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Coconut Chia Pudding</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/coconut_chia_pudding/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 19:51:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/coconut_chia_pudding/</guid><description>Ingredients Ingredient Subheading 1 can full-fat coconut milk 1 6 tablespoons chia seeds 1 tablespoon honey 1 teaspoon pure vanilla extract Pinch of salt Directions Mix all ingredients together. Cover and let sit overnight in refrigerator. Eat it in the morning. Top with raspberry jam or any compote if desired. Granola is also a good addition. Footnotes Thai Kitchen does not have very good or rich flavor. Get another brand.&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>5 Minute Nacho Cheese Sauce</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/cheese_sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 19:48:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/cheese_sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 Tbsp butter 2 Tbsp flour 1 cup whole milk 6 oz. medium cheddar, shredded (about 1.5 cups) 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 tsp chili powder Directions Add the butter and flour to a small sauce pot. Heat and whisk the butter and flour together until they become bubbly and foamy. Continue to cook and whisk the bubbly mixture for about 60 seconds. Whisk the milk into the flour and butter mixture.</description></item><item><title>Bruschetta</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/bruschetta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 19:45:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/bruschetta/</guid><description>Ingredients Tomatoes Garlic Onion Basil 1 Olive Oil Coarse Salt Directions Pile basil leaves on top of one another and roll into a log. Thinly slice basil into green confetti Dice tomatoes Loosely combine all ingredients without bruising them Footnotes Fresh from the garden makes all the difference&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>Beef Brisket</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/beef_brisket/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 19:40:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/beef_brisket/</guid><description>Ingredients Dry Rub Dark Brown Sugar Salt Pepper Onion Powder Garlic Powder Paprika Rosemary Parsely Chili powder Cayenne pepper Cumin Directions Apply dry rub to brisket Let it sit in the fridge for several hours or overnight Cook in the smoker with hickory chips at 225F at about an hour a pound Elevate the brisket while it’s in the smoker to help smoke reach all sides of the meat. When the meat reaches 165 to 170 remove it and double wrap with aluminum foil to keep juices from leaking out Brisket is done when temp reaches 190F Let rest for 1 to 2 hours Temp will continue to rise to 200F while resting Footnotes</description></item><item><title>Apple Crisp</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/apple_crisp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 19:37:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/apple_crisp/</guid><description>Ingredients 6 granny smith apples, peeled 1 tablespoon lemon juice 1/2 cup granulated sugar 1 1/4 cups + 2 tablespoons all purpose flour 1/2 cup old fashioned oats 1 cup brown sugar 1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon 1/4 teaspoon salt 12 tablespoons (1 1/2 stick) butter, chilled and cut into small pieces Vanilla ice cream Directions Preheat oven to 350F In a large mixing bowl toss together the apples, lemon juice, 1/2 cup granulated sugar, 1/2 cup brown sugar, 2 tbsp flour Let mixture rest in refrigerator In a separate mixing bowl mix the remaining 1 1/4 cups flour, oats, 1/2 cup brown sugar, cinnamon, and salt Work the butter into the mixture until it comes together and large clumps form Move apple mixture to 2 quart (9x9) greased baking dish Sprinkle the topping over the fruit Bake until fruit is bubbling and the topping is crispy and golden brown (about 45 minutes) Serve with ice cream</description></item><item><title>Mystery Pecan Pie</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/mystery_pecan_pie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 19:32:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/mystery_pecan_pie/</guid><description>Ingredients Crust 1 frozen pie crust Filling 1 package (8 oz) cream cheese, softened 1/3 cup sugar 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon vanilla 1 egg 3 eggs 1/4 cup sugar 1 cup corn syrup 1 teaspoon vanilla 1 1/4 cups chopped pecans Directions Place pie crust in 9-inch glass pie pan as directed on box for One-Crust Filled Pie. Heat oven to 375°F. In small bowl with electric mixer, beat cream cheese, 1/3 cup sugar, the salt, 1 teaspoon vanilla and 1 of the eggs on low speed until smooth and well blended; set aside.</description></item><item><title>Rice Pudding</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/rice_pudding_arborio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 17:48:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/rice_pudding_arborio/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup arborio rice 12 4 cups whole milk 1 can (14 oz) of Eagle brand sweetened condensed milk 3 1 1/2 tsp vanilla extract 1/4 tsp salt Ground cinnamon Butter Raisins (optional) Condended Milk Alternative 1/2 cup sugar 1 egg 1/4 cup heavy cream 1/4 cup milk Directions In a double-boiler 4, bring rice, milk, condensed milk, and salt to a boil Reduce heat, cover, and simmer for 1 hour Add vanilla and 1 tablespoon of butter Add raisins if desired Serve warm, top with butter and cinnamon Condended Milk Alternative Beat together sugar, egg, cream, and milk (or half and half) Stir mixture into rice Footnotes When cooking aroborio rice, minimize stirring as additional starch is realease when stirred.</description></item><item><title>Rice Pudding - Instant Pot</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/rice_pudding_instant_pot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 17:42:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/rice_pudding_instant_pot/</guid><description>Ingredients 5 cups milk (full fat) (Or almond milk if vegan) 1 cup water 1 1/2 cup basmati rice (Or any medium grain white rice, rinsed) 1/2 cup sugar adjust to taste 2 tsp cinnamon Directions Add water to the pot 1 Press saute Once the water begins to steam or boil, pour the milk into the pot Add rice Stir, wait for mixture to begin steaming Close lid, pressure cook on high for 20 minutes Allow natural pressure release for 20 minutes Press saute Add sugar and cinnamon Stir until incorporated and thickened Turn off instant pot Extras Add raisins when adding sugar and cinnamon Top with whipped cream Mash the rice once cooked for a creamier texture Footnotes You must boil the water in the instant pot before adding the milk in order to avoid scorching&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>Fluffy Pancakes</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/fluffy_pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 16:51:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/fluffy_pancakes/</guid><description>Ingredients Dry 3 c All purpose flour 1/4 c Sugar 1 1/2 tsp salt 1 tbsp baking powder 1 1/2 tsp baking soda Wet 2 1/4 c milk 1/4 c vegetable oil 1 tbsp vanilla extract 1/4 c apple cider vinegar 1 (optional) 1 egg, reduce milk by 1/4 cup if adding egg Whipped salted butter 1 stick of salted butter at room temperature 1 tbsp cold water Directions Pancakes Mix dry and wet in separate bowls.</description></item><item><title>Boiled Water</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/boiled_water/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 16:25:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/boiled_water/</guid><description>Ingredients Liquid Ingredients Water Directions Heat on High to 212F 1 Footnotes Water boils at 212F&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>Egg Nog - Uncooked</title><link>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/egg-nog-uncooked/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cookbook.lukebtaylor.com/egg-nog-uncooked/</guid><description>BE SURE TO REFRIGERATE THE EGGNOG AND SERVE ICE COLD. IF ANY SITS OUR ON A BUFFET TABLE VERY LONG, THROW IT OUT.
Ingredients 1 dozen eggs , separated 1 2 3 4 1/2 teaspoon salt 2 1/4 or more cups sugar 2 or more cups bourbon 1/2 cup rum 1 quart milk 2 tablespoons vanilla 3 pints heavy cream Directions Beat together the egg yolks and salt in a large mxing bowl, slowly adding 1 1/2 cups of the sugar.</description></item></channel></rss>